Class of 1892 Records, 1874-1954, 1970
Smith College Archives
Class of 1892 Records
1874-1954, 1970
Smith College. Class of 1892.
RG 80 UUID:68a6f2e7-d338-44ac-bda8-df8c0c8dd7f3
9 boxes (3 linear ft. and 9 linear inches)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains black and white photographs, correspondence, letters, diaries, scrapbooks, journals, and memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1892.
The Class of 1892 was the fourteenth graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1892 Records contain materials describing the history of the Class of 1892. Types of materials include black and white photographs, correspondence, letters, diaries, scrapbooks, journals, and memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1892.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1892 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Class of 1892: Baccalaureate Service (Box 1466, Folder 1)
- Class of 1892: Class Letters 1891-92, 1930-32, 1940 (Box 1466, Folder 2)
- Class of 1892: Commencement 1892 (Box 1466, Folder 3)
- Class of 1892: Commencement Music 1892 (Box 1466, Folder 4)
- Class of 1892: Freshman Grind by 1891 (Box 1466, Folder 5)
- Class of 1892: Groups- First Year 1888-89 (Box 1466, Folder 6)
- Class of 1892: Groups- Second Year 1889 (Box 1466, Folder 7)
- Class of 1892: Groups- Junior Year with J. Stoddard 1890-91 (Box 1466, Folder 8)
- Class of 1892: Groups- Senior Year and Art Students 1892 (Box 1466, Folder 9)
- Class of 1892: Groups- Small Groups 1888, 1891, other n.d. (Box 1466, Folder 10)
- Class of 1892: History 1889, other n.d. (Box 1466, Folder 11)
- Class of 1892: Ivy Day 1892 (Box 1466, Folder 12)
- Class of 1892: Junior Prom 1891 (Box 1466, Folder 13)
- Class of 1892: Parties 1891-92, other n.d. (Box 1466, Folder 14)
- Class of 1892: Questionnaire 1892 (Box 1466, Folder 15)
- Class of 1892: Records 1888-97, 1902, 1907, 1910, 1912, 1916-17, 1920-22, 1925-27, 1932, 1937, 1941-42 (Box 1466, Folder 16)
- Class of 1892: Reunions 1913, 1916, 1925, 1927, 1932, 1942, 1947 (Box 1467, Folder 1)
- Class of 1892: Reunions- Owls (Box 1467, Folder 2)
- Class of 1892: Reunion Photographs 1907, 1912-1913, 1947, other n.d. (Box 1467, Folder 3)
- Class of 1892: Reunion Songs 1902, 1912, 1927, 1932, other n.d. (Box 1467, Folder 4)
- Class of 1892: Reunion- 1937 1937 (Box 1467, Folder 5)
- Class of 1892: Reunion- 1962 1962 (Box 1467, Folder 6)
- Class of 1892: Seal 1892 (Box 1467, Folder 7)
- Class of 1892: Senior Dramatics- Music 1892 (Box 1467, Folder 8)
- Class of 1892: Senior Dramatics- Photographs 1892 (Box 1467, Folder 9)
- Class of 1892: Senior Dramatics- Programs 1892 (Box 1467, Folder 10)
- Class of 1892: Songs (Box 1467, Folder 11)
- Class of 1892: Sophomore Reception 1888 (Box 1467, Folder 12)
- Class of 1892: Class Supper 1892 (Box 1467, Folder 13)
- Class of 1892: Adams, Helena Belle 1892, other n.d. (Box 1468, Folder 1)
- Class of 1892: Austin, Martha 1898-1900, 1902, 1906-08, 1932-33 (Box 1468, Folder 2)
- Class of 1892: Ayres, Winifred 1892, 1895, 1915, 1926 (Box 1468, Folder 3)
- Class of 1892: Blanchard, Helen Train (Photographs) (Box 1468, Folder 4)
- Class of 1892: Boyd, Harriet Ann 1900-01, 1904-05 (Box 1468, Folder 5)
- Class of 1892: Bridges, Eliza Wadsworth McMechan (Photographs) 1891 (Box 1468, Folder 6)
- Class of 1892: Brown, Edith B. (Photographs, etc) 1897, 1902, 1912, other n.d. (Box 1468, Folder 7)
- Class of 1892: Burnham, Mary Eunice Lord (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 8)
- Class of 1892: Charles, Pauline N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 9)
- Class of 1892: Clark, Edith Lucia (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 10)
- Class of 1892: Coolidge, Cora H. 1924, 1931, 1954, other n.d. (Box 1468, Folder 11)
- Class of 1892: Crehore, Mary Louise (Photographs, etc) 1894, other n.d. (Box 1468, Folder 12)
- Class of 1892: Crofoot, Sara Elizabeth N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 13)
- Class of 1892: Curtis, Elnora Whitman 1908-10, 1913 (Box 1468, Folder 14)
- Class of 1892: Cushman, Ruth G. (Diaries) 1889-92 (Box 1468, Folder 15)
- Class of 1892: Cushman, Ruth G. (Letters, etc) 1888, 1890-91 (Box 1468, Folder 16)
- Class of 1892: Cushman, Ruth Gilman (Photographs) 1892 (Box 1468, Folder 17)
- Class of 1892: Cutler, Eleanor Evelyn (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 18)
- Class of 1892: De Land, Helen Parce 1951 (Box 1468, Folder 19)
- Class of 1892: Drew, Marion (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 20)
- Class of 1892: Folsom, Martha Thayer (Photographs) 1892, other n.d. (Box 1468, Folder 21)
- Class of 1892: Francis, Vida Hunt (Photographs, etc) 1912-13, 1922 (Box 1468, Folder 22)
- Class of 1892: Gilbert, Clara Culver (Photographs) (Box 1468, Folder 23)
- Class of 1892: Goodwin, Sarah (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 24)
- Class of 1892: Haven, Katherine Lillian 1908, other n.d. (Box 1468, Folder 25)
- Class of 1892: Hawks, Emma 1894 (Box 1468, Folder 26)
- Class of 1892: Henshaw, Mary Dana (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 27)
- Class of 1892: Hogan, Lucy Mary N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 28)
- Class of 1892: Howland, Elisabeth Collamore (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 29)
- Class of 1892: Hungerford, Katherine (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1468, Folder 30)
- Class of 1892: Jacobs, Harriet Ethel (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 1)
- Class of 1892: Jordan, Mary Adela (Photographs, etc) 1892, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 2)
- Class of 1892: Kerruish, Miriam Gertrude 1901 (Box 1469, Folder 3)
- Class of 1892: Kilbon, Amelia Jeanette (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 4)
- Class of 1892: Kimball, Martha Smith 1964-65 (Box 1469, Folder 5)
- Class of 1892: Langworthy, Jessica L. 1931-32, 1936, 1938, 1947, 1970 (Box 1469, Folder 6)
- Class of 1892: Learoyd, Elizabeth Abbot (Photographs) 1892, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 7)
- Class of 1892: Lord, Grace (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 8)
- Class of 1892: Lyon, Louise 1874-75, 1877, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 9)
- Class of 1892: MacDougall, Margaret (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 10)
- Class of 1892: McConway, Laura- Art Student (Group Photo) 1892 (Box 1469, Folder 11)
- Class of 1892: McConway, Laura- Art Student (Miscellaneous) 1888-91, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 12)
- Class of 1892: McMillan, Frances (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 13)
- Class of 1892: Mitchell, Eliza Lamb (Photographs) 1902 (Box 1469, Folder 14)
- Class of 1892: Nichols, Fanny Augusta 1891 (Box 1469, Folder 15)
- Class of 1892: Nichols, Helen Christine N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 16)
- Class of 1892: Nixon, Mary Stites (Photographs, etc) 1911-12, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 17)
- Class of 1892: Parsons, Harriet N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 18)
- Class of 1892: Pratt, Elsie Fay (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 19)
- Class of 1892: Pratt, Grace Tyler 1922 (Box 1469, Folder 20)
- Class of 1892: Putney, Carrie Maria (Photographs, etc) 1891, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 21)
- Class of 1892: Rankin, Mary Poland N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 22)
- Class of 1892: Richards, Martha Billings 1917-18, 1949 (Box 1469, Folder 23)
- Class of 1892: Rowley, Helen A. N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 24)
- Class of 1892: Safford, Anne Williston (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 25)
- Class of 1892: Sands, Helen Elizabeth (Photographs) (Box 1469, Folder 26)
- Class of 1892: Searl, Irlavere Jane (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 27)
- Class of 1892: Seaver, Etta Anne (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 28)
- Class of 1892: Shepard, Lillian Estella (Photographs) 1891, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 29)
- Class of 1892: Shipman, Carolyn (Photographs) 1900, 1912-13, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 30)
- Class of 1892: Smith, Bertha Linton (Correspondence) 1891 (Box 1469, Folder 31)
- Class of 1892: Smith, Bertha Linton (Photographs) 1889-92, 1898, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 32)
- Class of 1892: Smith, Mary Shannon 1890, 1893, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 33)
- Class of 1892: Steele, Caroline Lounsbury (Photographs) 1892 (Box 1469, Folder 34)
- Class of 1892: Stoddard, May Baldwin (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 35)
- Class of 1892: Twitchell, Julia Curtis (Box 1469, Folder 36)
- Class of 1892: Tyler, Lena Louise (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 37)
- Class of 1892: Underwood, Elizabeth (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1469, Folder 38)
- Class of 1892: Veeder, Jessie Budington (Photographs) (Box 1469, Folder 39)
- Class of 1892: Walbridge, Wilhelmina von Colson (Photographs) 1890 (Box 1469, Folder 40)
- Class of 1892: Wallin, Madeleine (Box 1469, Folder 41)
- Class of 1892: Waterman, Patty Lee 1905, 1916 (Box 1469, Folder 42)
- Class of 1892: Wheeler, Blanche Emily 1936 (Box 1469, Folder 43)
- Class of 1892: Wild, Laura Huldah 1898, 1913, 1916, 1921-23, 1930, other n.d. (Box 1469, Folder 44)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Box 1469, Folder 45)
- Class of 1892: Ayres, Winifred (Diary, Sept. 1888-Sept.1889) 1888-89 (Box 1469.1, Folder 1)
- Class of 1892: Ayres, Winifred (Diary, Sept. 1891-Mar. 1892) 1891-92 (Box 1469.1, Folder 2)
- Class of 1892: Ayres, Winifred (Diary, Mar. 1892-Aug. 1892) 1892 (Box 1469.1, Folder 3)
- Class of 1892: Ayres, Winifred (Diary, Jan. 1894-Dec. 1894) 1894 (Box 1469.1, Folder 4)
- Class of 1892: Ayres, Winifred (Scrapbook) Various dates (Box 1469.1)
- Class of 1892: Ayres, Winifred (Scrapbook- loose items) 1883, 1885, 1889, 1893-97, 1899, 1902, other n.d. (Box 1469.1, Folder 5)
- Class of 1892: Dennen, Grace Atherton (Journals- The Ebell, The Lyric West) 1898-99, 1922 (Box 1470, Folder 1)
- Class of 1892: Dennen, Grace Atherton (Journals- The Lyric West) 1921-22 (Box 1470, Folder 2)
- Class of 1892: Learoyd, Elizabeth Abbot (Scrapbook) Various dates (Box 1471)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- American Society for Psychical Research) 1907 (Box 1471.1, Folder 1)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Association of Collegiate Alumnae Boston Brach) 1892-1894 (Box 1471.1, Folder 2)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Florence Barry 1893) 1891-1894 (Box 1471.1, Folder 3)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Blake Barton) 1900-1908 (Box 1471.1, Folder 4)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Caroline "Corrie" "Psyche" Bourland 1893) 1891-1904 (Box 1471.1, Folder 5)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Gertrude Burnham) 1895-1898 (Box 1471.1, Folder 6)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Frances Darling 1893) 1892-1898 (Box 1471.1, Folder 7)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Edwin DeMerritte, Berkeley School, Boston, MA) 1888-1889 (Box 1471.1, Folder 8)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- May Florence Dickerson) 1892-1895 (Box 1471.1, Folder 9)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Mary "Mollie" Mitchell Dole ex-1893) 1892-1904 (Box 1471.1, Folder 10)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Olivia Howard Dunbar 1894) 1892-1903, other n.d. (Box 1471.1, Folder 11)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Marie Louise Easton) 1899, 1901 (Box 1471.1, Folder 12)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Edith Granger (?) 1891) 1890 (Box 1471.1, Folder 13)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Katherine Haven 1892) 1894-1907 (Box 1471.1, Folder 14)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Jennie Frances Hendrie ex-1892) 1890-1892 (Box 1471.1, Folder 15)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Susan A. Howard) N.d. (Box 1471.1, Folder 16)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Harry S. Jepson) 1894 (Box 1471.1, Folder 17)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Grace Landon 1893) 1889 (Box 1471.1, Folder 18)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Mary Landon 1893) 1889-1890 (Box 1471.1, Folder 19)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence-Grace Lane 1893) 1892-1894 (Box 1471.1, Folder 20)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Clara S. Lathrop) 1891 (Box 1471.1, Folder 21)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Grace Love 1893) 1892 (Box 1471.1, Folder 22)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Ethel C. Lowry) 1896 (Box 1471.1, Folder 23)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Christine Mansfield 1892) 1892-1893 (Box 1471.1, Folder 24)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Harriet C. Mills 1893) 1892 (Box 1471.1, Folder 25)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Herbert A. Morse) 1893 (Box 1471.1, Folder 26)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Charlotte "Lottie" Murkland 1893) 1891-1898 (Box 1471.1, Folder 27)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence-Bertha L. Noyes 1894) 1893 (Box 1471.1, Folder 28)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Florence Helen Paul 1891) 1898, 1904 (Box 1471.1, Folder 29)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Helen Peterson ex-1893) 1893 (Box 1471.1, Folder 30)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Adeline W. Procter 1893) 1892-1896 (Box 1471.1, Folder 31)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Frank H. Reed) 1906-1907 (Box 1471.1, Folder 32)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Florence May Scovill 1893) 1894-1904, other n.d. (Box 1471.1, Folder 33)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- William L. Scovill) 1903-1904 (Box 1471.1, Folder 34)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Amy Gertrude Smith) 1897-1898 (Box 1471.1, Folder 35)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Charlotte Timmerman ex-1893) 1890 (Box 1471.1, Folder 36)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Grace Waldo ex-1892) 1892-1902 (Box 1471.1, Folder 37)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Edith Watt) 1890 (Box 1471.1, Folder 38)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Marion Ballantyne White ex-1892) 1889-1904 (Box 1471.2, Folder 1)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Anne Williams) 1889 (Box 1471.2, Folder 2)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Roger Williams) 1899 (Box 1471.2, Folder 3)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Mabel Preston Wyatt 1893) 1891-1893 (Box 1471.2, Folder 4)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Mabel Preston Wyatt 1893) 1894-1903, other n.d. (Box 1471.2, Folder 5)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Evelyn Wyman ex-1894) 1891-1893 (Box 1471.2, Folder 6)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Correspondence- Unidentified) 1891-1910 (Box 1471.2, Folder 7)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Invitations) 1895-1905, other n.d. (Box 1471.2, Folder 8)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Miscellaneous) 1888, other n.d. (Box 1471.2, Folder 9)
- Class of 1892: Williams, Helen Rachel (Photographs) 1892 (Box 1471.2, Folder 10)